WILLIAM KENNEDY PAPERS (MSS132) 1926-2003
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Very Old Bones, 1983; 1988-1993; Undated; 10; 4.09 cu. ft.
  William Kennedy continued his writings about the Phelan family with Very Old Bones, his next installment in the "Albany Cycle" of novels published in 1992. This book is set in the 1950s in the city and narrated by Orson Purcell, the out-of-wedlock son of Peter Phelan. The majority of the series consists of manuscript drafts and edited copy, although there are a small number of files containing correspondence, publicity materials, articles and reviews, and excerpts of the novel published in magazines.
  - One Draft of Prologue, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Early Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Early Draft, October 1988 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Five Drafts with Author Notes, November-December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Two Drafts and Edited Pages, December 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Superseded Pages, January 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clean Copy of Winter 1989 Draft, No Editing, ca. January-March 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 1 Rewrites, June 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Four Working Drafts with Author Notes, June-July 1989 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cut and Edited Pages, September 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Four Drafts of Book I, Chapter 2 with Author Notes, October 1989 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Two Drafts of Superseded Rewrites, October 1989 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Two Drafts of Rewrites, October 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Three Complete Drafts, November 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Incomplete Draft, Pages 1-87, November 1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rewritten Pages, November 1989; Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - One Draft "New Master" Copy, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 4 Rewritten Pages with Author Edits, December 1989-January 1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Rewritten Pages, April-May 1990 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Edited and Rewritten Pages, June 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Complete Draft with Author Edits, July 1990 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Two Drafts of Book II's Chapter Three, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Complete Draft of Books I and II with Edits, Superseded September 1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Book III, Chapter 1 Rewrites, Superseded October 1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Edited Pages, Superseded April, November 1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - One Draft of Books I and II with Revisions, Superseded December 1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Book III Edited and Rewritten Pages, Superseded December 1990, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - One Unedited Draft, Pages 1-186, Missing Pages 142-150, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded January 1991, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Phelan Family Geology and Rewrites, Superseded February 1991, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Edited and Superseded Pages, Superseded March 1991, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - First Draft, Pages 1-195, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - First Draft, Pages 196-280, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Second Draft, Pages 1-197, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Second Draft, Pages 198-280, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Third Draft with Author Edits, Pages 1-197, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Third Draft with Author Edits, Pages 198-280, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded April-May 1991, Undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded June-July 1991, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Written and Edited Pages, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Fourth Draft with Author Edits, Pages 1-174, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fourth Draft with Author Edits, Pages 175-305, Superseded July 1991, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Draft, Unedited, Pages 1-174, July 1991 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Draft, Unedited, Pages 175-305, July 1991 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded August 1991, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Superseded September 1991, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Second to Last Draft, Pages 1-189, September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Second to Last Draft, Pages 190-361, September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Penultimate Draft, Copy, Pages 1-189, September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Penultimate Draft, Copy, Pages 190-361, September 1991 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Penultimate Draft, Pages 1-204, Sent October 1991, ca. September 1991 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Penultimate Draft, Pages 205-361, Sent October 1991, ca. September 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - "Final" Draft, Viking Copy, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - "Final" Draft, Viking Copy, Pages 190-363, October 1991 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Final Draft, A. Silverman Copy with Notes, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Final Draft, A. Silverman Copy with Notes, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Rewritten Pages, Superseded October-November 1991, Undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Photocopy of Penguin USA Manuscript, Pages 1-189, November 1991 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Penguin USA Manuscript, Pages 190-363, November 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Printer's Copy of Very Old Bones, Pages 1-189, October 1991 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Printer's Copy of Very Old Bones, Pages 190-363, October 1991 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Author's Set of Galley Proofs, December 1991 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Author's Set of Galley Proofs, with Handwritten Edits, December 1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Master Galleys, December 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Publicity Materials, 1990-1993; Undated (Box 11, Folder 5-6)
  - Rewritten Paragraphs for "Exile", December 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Viking Correspondence, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Publication Information, 1991-1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Playboy Excerpts, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - The Recorder, Volume 6, Number 1, Summer 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Articles, Reviews, Clippings, 1992; Undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - "Fan" Mail, 1992; Undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Playboy Corrected Galleys, 1992 (Oversized 6, Folder 1)
  - Book Reviews and Profiles, 1992 (Oversized 6, Folder 2)
- Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, 1946-1999; Undated; 11; 1.86 cu. ft.
  This series includes draft copy, galleys, research materials, correspondence, and notes used to prepare William Kennedy's Riding the Yellow Trolley Car, a collection of his essays, articles, and reviews written across four decades. This second nonfiction book from Kennedy appeared in 1993. Of note is the earliest item within the collection, a short story entitled "Eggs" from 1946 which Kennedy submitted to Collier's: The National Weekly for consideration. In addition there are files about publicity, including a book tour, reviews, and fan mail. Please note the overall dates for the series are not inclusive.
  - Short Story "Eggs", 1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Guys and Dolls Script and Articles, 1950-1992 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - John Steinbeck Information, 1962; 1968; 1989; Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Unused Articles with Notes, 1967-1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - One Draft "Roberta Sue Ficker", 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Articles and Author Notes Regarding Paul McCartney, 1969; Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photocopies of "Trolley Car" Articles, 1964-1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - One Draft of "Robert Penn Warren", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence and Articles, 1974; 1985; 1992-1993; Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Original William Kennedy Articles, 1974-1988; Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Kennedy Articles Used for Book I, 1982; 1985; Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Louis "Satchmo" Armstrong, Author Notes and Clippings, 1983; 1992; 1999; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notes and Photocopies, 1984; 1987; 1989-1990; 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Soto," Articles and Information, 1988; 1992; Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Drafts and Correspondence Regarding Article "Do the Homeless Have Souls?", 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Writings and Articles Regarding "Dana's Hiccups", 1989; 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - One Draft of "Norman Mailer Speech", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - "Two Grandfathers" Correspondence and Drafts, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Eight Drafts of "All My Days Are the Same", 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Viking Press, 1991-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notes and Drafts of the Table of Contents, 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Twelve Drafts of the "Introduction", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Copyright Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Nine Drafts of "Guys and Dolls," Writings, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Guys and Dolls Script Articles and Information, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Guys and Dolls Book Cover, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ten Drafts of "How I Became a Baseball Fan" with Author Notes, 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Four Drafts of "Has Anybody Here Seen Runyon?", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - First Set of Galley Proofs, 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 1)
  - Galleys, ca. 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Author's Set of Galleys, 1992 (Oversized 7, Folder 4-6)
  - Damon Runyon Information, 1992; 1994; Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1993 Book Tour Publicity, 1992-1993; Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Publicity, Correspondence, Clippings and Articles, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Galleys, Publicity, and Research Material, 1992-1993; Undated (Oversized 6, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of Book Materials, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fan Mail, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Reviews, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Viking Book Guide, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - "Robert Frost" Draft for National Observer, Undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of "Part One", Undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of "Part Two," Examining Writers, Undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of "Parts Three and Four", Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Photocopy of "Parts Five and Six", Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Photocopy of Pages 1-199, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of Pages 200-402, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Photocopy of Pages 403-494, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Riding the Yellow Trolley Car Bookcovers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Flaming Corsage, 1993-1997; 2001; Undated; 12; 2.93 cu. ft.
  For his next volume in his "Albany Cycle," William Kennedy returned to recurrent characters Edward and Katrina Daugherty, first introduced in Billy Phelan's Greatest Game. Kennedy charts their lives and subsequent, turbulent marriage in the city between 1884 and 1912 in The Flaming Corsage, published in 1996. The series includes multiple drafts and edited manuscripts, book tour materials, cover artwork, reviews, articles, correspondence, and information about the audio version of the book.
  - Prologue and Chapter One Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Chapter One Drafts, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Chapter Two Drafts, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Early Draft of Chapter 1 and 2, Summary, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Early Draft "Untitled Novel", 1994 February (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chapter 2 Drafts, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Chapter 3 Drafts, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - First Draft with Edited Pages, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Edward" Drafts, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Second Drafts, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Rewritten Pages, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Third Draft, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Partial "New" Third Draft, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Rewritten and Edited Pages, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3-4)
  - Partial Chronological Draft, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Incomplete Draft, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Photocopy of Complete Draft, 1995 May (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Photocopy of Complete Draft with Author Notes, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Second to Last Draft with Author Notes, Pages 1-220, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Second to Last Draft with Author Notes, Pages 221-271, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Incomplete Draft, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Draft with Edits, 1995 May (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
  - Working Copy of Draft for Viking, Pages 1-209, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Working Copy of Draft for Viking, Pages 210-293, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Final Draft, Pages 1-186, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Final Draft, Pages 187-293, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Master Copy of Final Draft, Pages 1-186, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Master Copy of Final Draft, Pages 187-293, Undated (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photocopies of Final Draft, Pages 93-293, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Photocopy of Viking Draft, Pages 1-190, Undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Viking Draft, Pages 191-293, Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Copy of John McElroy Draft, Pages 1-153, 1995 November (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Copy of John McElroy Draft, Pages 154-209, 1995 November (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - William Kennedy Rejected Cuts, Pages 1-164, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - William Kennedy Rejected Cuts, Pages 165-293, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Copy Viking Proofs, 1995 December (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Selected Pages Read by the Author, Pages 1-111, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Selected Pages Read by the Author, Pages 112-227, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Audio Story Information, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Book Covers, Art, and Correspondence, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fan Mail and Reactions, 1995-1996; 2001 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Viking/Penguin Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Book Tour Information, 1995-1997 (Box 8, Folder 2-3)
  - Publisher's Weekly, 1996 March 04 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Viking Book Guide, 1996 May-1996 August (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of Proof Pages, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Franklin Library Edition Information, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Readings and Announcements, 1996; Undated (Oversized 6, Folder 4)
  - Book Reviews and Profiles, 1996-1997 (Oversized 6, Folder 5)
  - Publicity Clippings and Notes, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Articles and Reviews, 1995-1996; Undated (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
  - Spanish Reviews and Articles, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Two Writing Responses to William Kennedy's Novels, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Roscoe, 1996-2000; Undated; 13; 3.3 cu. ft.
  This series consists of manuscript drafts, edited copy, and reviews for Roscoe. Published in 2002, it is part of William Kennedy's "Albany Cycle" of novels. Opening in 1945 Albany, Roscoe centers around Roscoe Conway, a decades-long insider of the Democartic Party and the political machine in the capital city.
  - Working Drafts of You Can Imagine How Mac Felt, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Working Drafts of Chapters 1 and 2, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Working Drafts of Chapter 3, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Drafts of Chapters 1-3, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Chapters 1-3 Rewrites and Edits, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Working Drafts of Chapters 4 and 5, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Rewrites (Folder 1 of 3), 1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Rewrites (Folders 2 and 3 of 3), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Rewrites and Edited Pages (Folders 1-3 of 6), 1999 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Rewrites and Edited Pages (Folders 4-6 of 6), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
  - Reading Drafts for Skidmore and AWP-WI, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Rewrites, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Complete Penultimate Draft, September 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Rewrites, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
  - Rewriten and Edited Pages, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Partial Draft, Pages 1-214, January 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Harry Staley's Copy of Roscoe, Pages 1-214, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Harry Staley's Copy of Roscoe, Pages 215-425, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - Chapter 5, First Computer Draft and Rewrites, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - "Roscoe Among the Saints" Edits and Rewrites, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Rewrites and Edits (Folders 1-4 of 6), 2000 (Box 6, Folder 2-5)
  - Rewrites and Edits (Folders 5 and 6 of 6), 2000 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Roscoe Reading Excerpts, 2000-2001 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Rewrites and Edits, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
  - Revised Pages, January 2001 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Paul Slovak's Copy of Penultimate Draft, Pages 1-211, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Paul Slovak's Copy of Penultimate Draft, Pages 212-415, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Final Draft for Viking, Pages 1-209, February 2001 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Final Draft for Viking, Pages 210-412, February 2001 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Final Draft with Word Count, Pages 1-209 (Folder 1 of 2), February 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Final Draft with Word Count, Pages 210-412 (Folder 2 of 2), February 2001 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Edited and Rejected Pages, 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Proofreader's Edited Copy of Roscoe, Pages 1-209, Undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Proofreader's Edited Copy of Roscoe, Pages 210-412, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Photocopy of Rough Pages, Pages 1-146 (Folder 1 of 2), June 2001 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Photocopy of Rough Pages, Pages 147-292 (Folder 2 of 2), June 2001 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - "Author's Note" Drafts, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence and Notes, 2001 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Articles and Reviews, 2001-2002 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Author's Rough Pages, Pages 1-146, January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Copy of Author's Rough Pages, Pages 147-292, January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Palace Theater Readings, January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Helen and Harry Staley Reading Notes, January 2002 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Galley Copy of Roscoe, February 2002 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- The Albany Cycle, 1976; 1996; 2001-2002; 14; .66 cu. ft.
  In 1996 and 2002 publishers packaged together several of William Kennedy's "Albany Cycle" novels into single volumes for release in the United States and international market. In 1996 Penguin Books released Legs, Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, and Ironweed together for the first time with a new author's introduction. Six years later Scribner, an imprint of Simon & Schuster UK, published two books each containing three re-issued "Albany Cycle" novels. The first consisted of Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, Ironweed, and Very Old Bones. The second featured Quinn's Book, The Flaming Corsage, and Legs. This series includes materials related to these publications as well as a 1976 outline by Kennedy of his vision for the "Albany Cycle" of planned books, and correspondence and proposed artwork for paperback copies of "Albany Cycle" novels issued from Penguin in 2002.
  - William Kennedy's "Statement of Plans" for Albany Cycle, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Albany Cycle: Introduction to Legs-Billy-Ironweed Volume, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Galley of Legs from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Galley of Billy Phelan's Greatest Game from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Galley of Ironweed from the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Book Cover Matter for the Albany Cycle/Trilogy, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Drafts, Author Notes, and Preface for Albany Cycle in Paperback, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Albany Cycle Correspondence, Reviews, and Book Matter for Paperback Editions, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book I Billy Phelan's Greatest Game, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book II Ironweed, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part I, Book III Very Old Bones, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book IV Quinn's Book, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book V The Flaming Corsage, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Galley of Albany Cycle, Part II, Book VI Legs, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Essays and Articles, 1963-1970; 1972; 1978-1998; 2002; Undated; 15; 2.03 cu. ft.
  Spanning several decades, this series features William Kennedy's essays and a news articles written for such varied outlets as newspapers, magazines, a city guide, a writers' cook book, a National Endowment for the Humanities Project, and a museum. In many instances, the files also include supplemental materials such as research, notes, and correspondence. Please note this series does not contain Kennedy's feature articles for the Albany Times-Union in the mid-1960s on slums, housing integration or poverty. These may be found in Series 17: Investigative Journalism.
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts, August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Notes by S. Dumbleton and Joe [Gagen], August 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Author's Editing, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Drafts with Author's Editing, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Albany: The Lively, Improbable Mosaic Europe Created," Final Draft, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "The Capitol in Albany," Introduction, Drafts and Final, 1984; Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Perry Duryea," Drafts and Author Notes for New York Times Article, 1972; Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Empire State College, Courses, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Getting It All, Saving It All," Correspondence, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Drafts of "Getting It All, Saving It All," Edited, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Grandma Moses, 1963; Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence and Articles Regarding Edward Hopper Publication, 1994-1995; 1997; Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Oversized Edward Hopper Materials, 1995; Undated (Oversized 8, Folder 1)
  - Galley Photocopy of "Edward Hopper and the American Imagination", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - "Letter to the Reader,"Zoetropes, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Masters of Deception, Research, 1963-1997 (Box 2, Folder 3-5)
  - Masters of Deception, Correspondence, 1997; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Masters of Deception, Transcribed Notes of Interviews, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Several Drafts of "Wag the Dog," For George Magazine, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Interviews and Notes Regarding "Wag the Dog," Article, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Travel Diary, Personal and Production Notes on"Wag the Dog", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - "Masters of Deception"/"Wag the Dog" News Clippings, 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - "Masters of Deception" Page Proofs and Oversized Materials, 1997; Undated (Oversized 8, Folder 2)
  - "Mr. Lonely Hearts," Information, Draft, and Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - "Negative Cooking, Negative Eating," from The Great American Writers' Cookbook, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - New Paltz, 1964; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1963 September 01-1967 December 31 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1968 January 07-1968 December 29 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1969 January 19-1969 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1970 January 04-1970 October 04 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings of Interest That Relate to Articles - Not Photocopied, 1963-1965 (Oversized 8, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings Written by Kennedy - Photocopied, 1965-1970 (Oversized 8, Folder 4)
  - "One Day in Albany," Correspondence, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - "One Day in Albany," Drafts, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - "One Day in Albany," Notes, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - "One Day in Albany," Research, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - "One Day in Albany,"Times-Union Reprint, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Author Notes, Drafts and Documents Regarding Articles About Papal Visit, 1965; Undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - "The Peopling of America," Research Notes, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 14)